<Recipe xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
	<Title>Beef Chili with Beans</Title>
	<ImageURL>
		http://a.dilcdn.com/bl/wp-content/uploads/sites/8/2011/11/pump-chili.jpg
	</ImageURL>
	<Ingredients>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 2 tablespoons vegetable or corn oil </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 2 cups onions; chopped - cut into 1/4-inch pieces </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 1 cup bell pepper; chopped (red, yellow or green) - cut into 1/2-inch pieces</Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 2 tablespoons garlic; minced (or pressed through garlic press) </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 4 tablespoons chili powder; (Spice Islands brand adds great flavor) </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 1 tablespoon Ground cumin </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 2 teaspoons Ground coriander </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 1 teaspoon crushed red pepper flakes </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 1 teaspoon dried Mexican oregano </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 1/2 teaspoon Cayenne pepper </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 2 pounds ground beef; (preferably coarse ground and 85 percent lean) </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 2 15-oz cans red kidney beans; - drained and rinsed </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 1 28-oz can diced tomatoes; - with juice </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> 1 28-oz can tomato puree </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> table salt </Name>
		</Ingredient>
		<Ingredient>
			<Name> Original recipe makes 8 </Name>
		</Ingredient>
	</Ingredients>
	<Instructions>
		Heat oil in a large heavy-bottomed nonreactive saucepot or Dutch oven mediun heat. When oil is shimmering, add the onions, bell pepper, garlic, chili powder, cumin, coriander, pepper flakes, oregano, and cayenne. (Dry seasonings are added at the beginning with the onions so the spices release their oils and the vegetables have enough time to absorb all the flavors.) Cook the mixture, stirring occasionally, until vegetables are softened and lightly colored, about 10 minutes.

		Increase heat to medium-high, add half the beef and lightly season with about 1/4 teaspoon salt. Cook, breaking up the meat with a wooden spoon, until no longer pink and just beginning to brown, roughly 4 to 5 minutes. Add remaining beef and lightly season again with about 1/4 teaspoon salt. Cook, breaking up the meat with a wooden spoon, until no longer pink, another 4 to 5 minutes.

		Add beans, tomatoes and their juices, tomato puree, and about 1/2 teaspoon salt. Bring to a boil, then reduce heat to low and simmer, covered, for 1 hour, stirring occasionally. Remove lid and continue to simmer for another hour, stirring occasionally, until meat is tender and chili is slightly thickened (if chili begins to stick to bottom of pot, stir in 1/2 cup water and continue to simmer). Taste and, if necessary, adjust seasoning with salt. Remove from heat and serve, or refrigerate, and serve the next day. To serve, ladle into bowls, and top with your favorite condiments.
	</Instructions>
</Recipe>